WENHU CHEN

Location: Santa Barbara, Phone: (805)455-1121, Email: wenhuchen@ucsb.edu Website: https://wenhuchen.github.io/, Github: https://github.com/wenhuchen

ABOUT ME

I'm currently a Ph.D student in Computer Science Department of University of California, Santa Barbara supervised by William Wang and Xifeng Yan. My research interests lie in natural language processing and deep learning. Primarily, I work on natural language processing under structured or semi-structured data like tables [23,21,20,18,15], KB [22,17,4], etc. I'm mainly interested in tasks like question answering [21,19], text generation [22,20,18,11], fact-checking [16,15] and other related understanding tasks [10,7]. Besides, I'm also interested in variational inference [12,8,4], multi-modality problems [19,16,5,2], and machine translation [6,3,1], etc. My research goal is to bring together free-form textual knowledge and structured symbolic knowledge to build the new-generation AI system.

CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

[23] Open Question Answering over Tables and Text

Wenhu Chen, Ming-Wei Chang, Eva Schlinger, William Yang Wang, William W. Cohen

[22] KGPT: Knowledge-Grounded Pre-Training for Data-to-Text Generation

Wenhu Chen, Yu Su, Xifeng Yan, William Yang Wang. Proceedings of EMNLP 2020

[21] HybridQA: A Dataset of Multi-Hop Question Answering over Tabular and Textual Data Wenhu Chen, Hanwen Zha, Zhiyu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, Hong Wang, William Wang. Proceedings of EMNLP

Wennu Chen, Hanwen Zha, Zhiyu Chen, Wennan Xiong, Hong Wang, William Wang. Proceedings of EMNLF 2020 (Findings)

[20] Logic2Text: High-Fidelity Natural Language Generation from Logical Forms

Zhiyu Chen, <u>Wenhu Chen</u>, Hanwen Zha, Xiyou Zhou, Yunkai Zhang, Sairam Sundaresan, William Yang Wang. Proceedings of EMNLP 2020 (Findings)

[19] Meta Module Network for Compositional Visual Reasoning

Wenhu Chen, Zhe Gan, Linjie Li, Yu Cheng, William Wang, Jingjing Liu. Proceedings of WACV 2021, Hawaii, USA (Oral)

[18] Logical Natural Language Generation from Open-Domain Tables

Wenhu Chen, Jianshu Chen, Yu Su, Zhiyu Chen and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of ACL 2020, Seattle, USA (Long)

[17] Few-shot NLG with Pre-trained Language Model

Zhiyu Chen, Harini Eavani, Wenhu Chen, Yinyin Liu and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of ACL 2020, Seattle, USA (Short)

[16] VIOLIN: A Large-Scale Dataset for Video-and-Language Inference

Jingzhou Liu, Wenhu Chen, Yu Cheng, Zhe Gan, Licheng Yu, Yiming Yang, Jingjing Liu. Proceedings of CVPR 2020, Seattle, USA (Poster)

[15] TabFact: A Large-scale Dataset for Table-based Fact Verification

<u>Wenhu Chen, Hongmin Wang, Jianshu Chen, Yunkai Zhang, Hong Wang, Shiyang Li, Xiyou Zhou and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of ICLR 2020, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia (Poster)</u>

[14] Generative Adversarial Zero-Shot Relational Learning for Knowledge Graphs

Pengda Qin, Xin Wang, <u>Wenhu Chen</u>, Chunyun Zhang, Weiran Xu, William Yang Wang. Proceedings of AAAI 2020, New York, USA (Oral)

[13] Enhancing the Locality and Breaking the Memory Bottleneck of Transformer on Time Series Forecasting

Shiyang Li, Xiaoyong Jin, Yao Xuan, Xiyou Zhou, <u>Wenhu Chen</u>, Yu-Xiang Wang, Xifeng Yan. Proceedings of NeurIPS 2019, Vancouver, Canada (Poster)

[12] Interpreting and Improving Deep Neural SLU Models via Vocabulary Importance

Yilin Shen, Wenhu Chen, Hongxia Jin. Proceedings of INTERSPEECH 2019, Graz, Austria (Oral)

[11] Semantically Conditioned Dialog Response Generation via Hierarchical Disentangled Self-Attention

Wenhu Chen, Jianshu Chen, Pengda Qin, Xifeng Yan and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of ACL 2019, Florence, Italy (Long Poster)

[10] Global Textual Relation Embedding for Relational Understanding

Zhiyu Chen, Hanwen Zha, Honglei Liu, <u>Wenhu Chen</u>, Xifeng Yan and Yu Su. Proceedings of ACL 2019, Florence, Italy (Short Poster)

[9] Mining Algorithm Roadmap in Scientific Publications

Hanwen Zha, Wenhu Chen, Keqian Li and Xifeng Yan. Proceedings of KDD 2019, Alaska, USA (Research Track, Oral)

[8] How Large A Vocabulary Does Text Classification Need? A Variational Approach on Vocabulary Selection

Wenhu Chen, Yu Su, Yilin Shen, Zhiyu Chen, Xifeng Yan and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of NAACL 2019, Minneapolis, USA (Long Oral)

[7] XL-NBT: A Cross-lingual Neural Belief Tracking Framework

Wenhu Chen, Jianshu Chen, Yu Su, Xin Wang, Dong Yu, Xifeng Yan and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of EMNLP 2018, Brussel, Belgium (Long Paper)

[6] Triangular Architecture for Rare Language Translation

Shuo Ren, Wenhu Chen, Shujie Liu, Mu Li, Ming Zhou and Shuai Ma. Proceedings of ACL 2018, Melbourne, Australia (Long Oral)

[5] No Metrics Are Perfect: Adversarial Reward Learning for Visual Storytelling

Wenhu Chen*, Xin Wang*, Yuan-Fang Wang and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of ACL 2018, Melbourne, Australia (Long Oral)

[4] Variational Knowledge Graph Reasoning

Wenhu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, William Yang Wang, Xifeng Yan. Proceedings of NAACL 2018, New Orleans, USA (Long Oral)

[3] Generative Bridging Network in Neural Sequence Prediction

Wenhu Chen, Guanlin Li, Shuo Ren, Shujie Liu, Zhirui Zhang, Mu Li, Ming Zhou. Proceedings of NAACL 2018, New Orleans, UAS (Long Poster)

[2] Video Captioning via Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning

Xin Wang, <u>Wenhu Chen</u>, Jiawei Wu, Yuan-fang Wang, William Yang Wang. Proceedings of CVPR 2018, Salt Lake City, USA (Poster)

[1] Guided alignment training for topic-aware neural machine translation

Wenhu Chen, Evgeny Matusov, Shahram Khadivi, JT Peter. AMTA 2016, Austin, TX (Poster)

SERVICE

2018: Program Committee in Socal-NLP, EMNLP

2019: Program Committee in AAAI, NAACL, ICML, ACL, NeurIPS, TACL, EMNLP

2020: Program Committee in AAAI, ACL, ICML, EMNLP, NeurIPS

2021: Program Committee in ICLR

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Barbara

Sep 2017-Now

Ph.D in Computer Science

Advisor: Xifeng Yan and William Wang

Overall GPA: 3.95/4.0

ETH Zurich, Switzerland

Visiting in Computer Science

Overall GPA: 6.0/6.0

June 2016-Dec 2016

RWTH Aachen University, Germany

M.Sc. in Electronics Engineering

Overall GPA: 1.4/1.0

Huazhong University of Science and Technology, China

Sep 2010-June 2014

Sep 2014-Dec 2016

B.Sc. in Electronics Engineering

Overall GPA: 86/100

EXPERIENCE

Google ResearchSep 2020 - Dec 2020Student Researcher ProgramPittsburgh, USA

· Work on Open-Domain Question Answering Systems

Google Research

June 2020 - Sep 2020

Research Intern Pittsburgh, USA

· Designed Open-Domain Question Answering Systems

Microsoft AI & Cloud

June 2019 - Sep 2019

Research Intern

Bellevue, USA

· Designed modular network for visual question answering (CVPR 2020, WACV 2021)

Samsung Research America

June 2018 - Sep 2018

Research Intern

Mountain View, USA

· Designed model compression algorithm for NLP tasks (NAACL 2019, INTERSPEECH 2019)

Microsoft Research Asia Feb 2017 - Aug 2017

Research Intern Beijing, China

· Designed data-augmentation algorithm for sequence learning (NAACL 2018, ACL 2018)

eBay Research December 2015 - June 2016

Research Intern

Aachen, Germany

· Investigated the usage of statistical alignment in neural machine translation (AMTA 2016)

AWARD

Tencent AI Gift Award: Awarded the Tencent AI Gift Fund for PhD sponsorship.

IDEA Research Grant: Awarded IDEA research scholarship for exchange program in ETH.

German National Scholarship: Awarded a one-year scholarship sponsored by Robert Bosch Inc.

China Scholarship Committee Scholarship: Awarded full scholarship from CSC for a one-year exchange program in Germany.

MCM Finalist Award: Ranked top 0.5% in The Mathematical Contest in Modeling in 2013.